

Senior Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Support, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Debugging, Core Java, Pega PRPC, Oracle, MySQL, HTML



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 2 Month(s)

Current Company: Incessant Technologies, an Coforge DPA Highest Degree: M.Tech [Computers]

Private Limited

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Senior Software Engineer/Developer,Software Engineering,Software Development,Application Support,Project Management,Change Management,Defect Management,Quality Management,Requirement Gathering,Debugging,Core

Java, Pega PRPC, Oracle, MySQL, HTML

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Summary

Having around 4.2 years of relevant experience in design and implementation of Pega PRPC.

Hands on experience on HTML user interface using Rule-Html-Harness, Rule-Html-Section and Rule-Obj-Html. Hands on experience on Rule-Obj-Activity's and steps for business logic implementation and handling embedded pages. Hands on experience in Implementation of Declarative Processing Features Expressions, Constraints, Decision Rules like Decision Table, Decision tree.

Team player with good communication and interpersonal skills.

Ability to understand Functional Requirements and Use Case Documents and implementing the business rules using Pega. Identification of Properties and design of Flows based on the requirements.

Strong in Debugging Skills in PRPC with TRACER, Clipboard and UI Inspector.

Work Experience

Incessant Technologies, an Coforge DPA Private Limited as Senior Software Engineer Jun 2020 to Till Date

Client Standard Chartered Bank (SCB) Chennai

Role Developer Technology PRPC v8.1 Duration June 2020 to Till Date

Team Size 3

Project

Description Periscope:

Periscope is an existing application used within bank to manage various modules like Client Initiative, Control and Conduct, Score cards etc. This application is rich in graphs with basic workflow capabilities.

Periscope application is build using third party software which is rich in graphs and basic workflows. This application is managed by the third part vendor and the cost of maintenance is too High. Hence architects have decided to build this application in COOL platform.

Solution:

The solution is to build an periscope application in COOL platform using MSTR (Micro strategy) and following are the feature of this application:

- 1. MSTR is used to create all rich charts.
- 2. Periscope application in COOL platform is used to provide workflow capabilities.
- 3. MSTR charts are embedded in Periscope application to provide seamless experience to Pega.
- 4. SSO integration b/w Periscope and MSTR application.
- * Used agile studio for Scrum activities.
- * Worked on Case type Design, Flows, Flow actions.
- * Involved in the design and development of project.
- Worked on developing User Interface using Sections, Harness and Flow Actions.
- * Created Data models, Activities and Activity step methods, Decision Rules, Report definition rules and Validation Rules.
- * Involved in daily meetings and code reviews.
- * Performed Testing and debugging of the application using Tracer, Rules Inspector, Clipboard.

LTI - Larsen & Toubro Infotech as Software Engineer

Jul 2016 to Jun 2020

Client Procter & Gamble (P&G)

Role Developer

Technology PRPC v7.4

Duration SEP 2019 to Jan 2020

Team Size 12

Project

Description APSA- Annual Plant Standard setting process Automation, is to orchestrate around 1.5 million volume of active codes (for plant and material combination) and updating the process with new or old pricings based on the approvals from regional managers.

P&G has many plants in various regions, this application will support and automate the annual costing on each fiscal year (Jan to June) for all the regions, based on plant and material combinations.

- Used agile studio for Scrum activities.
- * Worked on Case type Design, Flows, Flow actions.
- * Involved in the design and development of project.
- * Worked on developing User Interface using Sections, Harness and Flow Actions.
- * Created Data models, Activities and Activity step methods, Decision Rules, Report definition rules and Validation Rules.
- * Involved in daily meetings and code reviews.
- * Performed Testing and debugging of the application using Tracer, Rules Inspector, Clipboard.

Project: 3

Client Pension Disbursement Management System(e-Pragati)

Role Developer

Technology PRPC v7.3.1

Duration JAN 2018 to AUG 2019

Team Size 8

Project

Description PDMS application provides platform for the department officials to manage the Pension Disbursement of Agricultural Marketing Committee employees. It helps end users to Add/ Edit the Pensioner details, DA arrear calculations, bank reconciliation process and reconciliation report handling. PDMS is single point solution for pensioners to upload the life certificates, access the pension statement and reports.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- * Experience on creating Data Model components Properties, Data Page, Edit-Validate, Data Transforms.
- Experience in creating Decision Rules (Decision Tree & Table).
- * Experience in Creating Declarative Rule, Declare Expressions, Declare On change, When condition as per the project requirements.
- * Experience on creating Process Rules (Flow Action and Validate).
- * Good Experience on Report Definition.
- * Experience in Activities
- * Created User Interfaces and modified the User Interface Rules (Harness, Sections) as per the requirements.
- * Experience on working with FLOW (Process Flows, Screen Flows and Sub Flows).
- * Extensive debugging Skills in PRPC using Clipboard & Tracer.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (JNTU) in 2011

PG: M.Tech (Computers) from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (JNTU) in 2014

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Pega Rules Process Commander v 7.x			
Core java, Oracle, MySQL, PRPC			
WINDOWS XP and WINDOWS 7			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Telugu				

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time